What sorts of activities can threaten the elements of the CIA Triad
consider a coworker sharing passwords.
Perhaps Joe gives Joanne his password because he is homesick and needs
Joanne to sign into his work computer to get information he needs.
But later, Joanne is fired from her job.
The employer cancels Joanne's credentials but isn't
aware that Joanne also knows Joe's password.
Joanne is disgruntled and decides to take revenge on her old
company by using Joe's credentials to change or delete important files
or in less hostile circumstances.
Improper use of the password could accidentally result in the
introduction of unauthorized software that is riddled with malware.
Another example is the laptop of a remote worker
being left unattended or unlocked in the worker's home.
Children or other family members may decide to play games on the computer.
They upload legal but contaminated software or files
leading to a corrupt workstation with compromised integrity.
The elements of the CIA triad can also be
compromised by ill preparedness against acts of nature.
For instance,
a long term power outage may lead to backup generators that run
out of fuel or that suffer mechanical failures if not properly maintained
as a final example,
improper fire suppression methods can affect the CIA triad by
irreparably damaging or destroying both digital and analog information.
All these examples show that a comprehensive risk assessment
of technical human and environmental threats must be completed,
then appropriate mitigation options must be put in place to
protect the security and integrity of an organization's information.